<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Egor Vidmaer</title>
    <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Egor Vidmaer</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Egor Vidmaer</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/event/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Hugo Blox Builder&amp;rsquo;s 
 feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using 
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including 
 such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post on classes 2-7 september</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/post/summary1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/post/summary1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;произошедшее-на-неделе&#34;&gt;Произошедшее на неделе&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I mastered new subjects that appeared in the second year.
Also this week I was actively involved in sports, went to the gym, attended physical education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the work week, I attended English courses and spent time with friends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the weekend I did self-development, finished reading a book and cooked food for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT in education new opportunities</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/it-in-edu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/it-in-edu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT is transforming education, providing new opportunities for learning and
development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online courses and MOOC (Massive Open Online Course) platforms: provide access to quality education from anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual reality and augmented reality: allow you to create more interactive and memorable lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence in education: helps to personalize learning and adapt it to the individual needs of students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT in education opens up new horizons and makes education more accessible,
interactive and effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember: this is only a small part of the vast world of IT and AI. The world of technology
is constantly evolving, and we must be aware of the latest trends and opportunities it offers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Fighting the Invisible Enemy</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/cybersec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/cybersec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the digital world, cybersecurity has become an integral part of our
life. Hackers and cybercriminals are constantly looking for new ways to hack systems,
steal data, and discredit organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect yourself from cyber threats, you need to take a number of measures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use strong passwords and multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update your software and operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use antivirus software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be wary of phishing attacks and do not click on suspicious links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a backup copy of important data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a constant struggle, but with proactive measures and awareness, we can protect ourselves from cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain is more than cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is often associated with cryptocurrencies, but the technology has a much broader range of applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is a distributed database that provides secure, transparent, and immutable records of information. It is used in a variety of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;areas, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial services: to transfer money faster and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supply chain management: to track the movement of goods and ensure their origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthcare: to securely store medical data and control access to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public administration: to transparently and efficiently maintain registries and documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain promises to revolutionize many industries and has the potential to change the way we interact with information and systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning how it works</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/deeplearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/deeplearning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep learning is one of the most popular and rapidly developing areas of
AI. But how exactly does it work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a multi-layered neural network, similar to the human brain.
Each layer processes data and extracts specific information from it.
For example, the first layer can recognize edges and shapes in an image, the second can
combine these shapes into more complex structures, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of huge data sets and powerful computing systems, the network &amp;ldquo;learns&amp;rdquo;
to recognize patterns, identify dependencies and make predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning allows you to create a system for speech recognition, language translation, medical diagnostics, self-driving cars and many other
technologies that change our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence is not a panacea, but a tool</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/publication/ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) is no longer just a buzzword, but a reality that is changing our lives. From smart assistants to medical diagnostics, AI is penetrating all areas. But it is important to understand that AI is not a panacea. It is a powerful and promising tool, but it requires a careful and balanced approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember that AI is a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; algorithm trained on data. The quality of the data and the correct creation of the model determine its effectiveness. Lack of data, bias in training information can lead to incorrect decisions, discrimination and undesirable consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI will not replace humans. It will help us solve problems, but control and responsibility remain with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://egorvidmaer.github.io/en/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
